here we're gonna look at a few
situations in my match against Dennis or
culo from the whirlpool masters a few
years back the Masters that I that are
one but in that tournament I had to play
Dennis and Dennis had my number big-time
he beat me I think the last seven and
eight matches seven or eight matches in
a row and I drew him in this tournament
and I wasn't too pleased because I knew
my form wasn't really there yet because
of the injury I had faced I had prepared
of course very lightly to not do more
damage to the elbow that was recovering
so in this match this is the second
round match I fell behind five to three
and I made a bunch of errors so I'm not
feeling too great at this moment so I
just want to walk you through my mental
frame of mind that I'm working on right
here
first of all I've made errors like I
said I'm playing an opponent that I've
lost too many times so you can call this
opponent tilt which I go through in the
course very interesting stuff and my
method of not playing Dennis but playing
the game is actually super focusing on
the execution of the game so I'm
focusing right here what I was doing in
the chair when we started this video is
I'm focusing on breathing I'm focusing
on my game plan so my or internal
discussions my internal talk it's like
try to execute the shots as good as you
can try to be composed as much as you
can
that's the things I'm saying to myself
in the chair and I'm focusing a lot on
my breathing because I'm not feeling
comfortable at this moment on that shot
they're all I could do is try to
separate the balls create distance
hopefully the one was going back up
table which it didn't so I'm sticking to
my guns I'm thinking I'm thinking well
right here that's where the breathing
kicks in if you're if you're breathing
well you get enough oxygen into your
brain to keep thinking straight because
if you start panicking and your
breathing goes down that's when your
mind starts going down so Dennis didn't
fully hook me but I still have to kick
it at this ball and again I'm thinking
pretty clearly here I want to hit it two
rails from behind boom and I want to get
it by that three and to the four five
nine which just doesn't work
but once again good thinking so I'm not
as disappointed there you know I'm
trying my best I'm still leaving him a
tough shot so let's see what happens
here on this shot Dennis chooses to jack
it up elevate the cue stick I think
maybe here I would prefer to roll the
ball and just go into the three and take
it from there because jacking up when
you're so short to the rail is really
difficult but if you're feeling good of
course you can do it and then this is
one of the better shot makers on the
tour so let's see
he rattles that ball and here is an
opportunity for me to get back into this
matches erase the eight so this is a
pivotal game if I lose this game I'm
down six three
he's breaking he's probably feeling a
lot better than now it's five three my
shot so now I reverse the the feeling a
little bit I'm happy that I get this
opportunity but it's not really an easy
layout as you can see the four ball I
can't make it here in this right corner
the five is blocking it and I couldn't
make it in the left corner either so I
have to get an angle like I did here to
get to the other side of the four and
try to make it in the side pocket so
like I explained earlier I'm not feeling
great here I'm nervous I made some
mistakes but I'm sticking to my game
plan I'm sticking to my breathing and
I'm trying to play the game as good as I
can that's all I'm thinking here take
baby steps one shot at a time guys that
sometimes all you can do when you're
feeling a little bit poor or a little
bit weak I should say so here again I'm
just trying to make sure of my angle the
side pockets on the restaurant tables
are pretty tricky and I got a a slight
angle so I don't want to take it for
granted I just want to stay under the
six so now I can come off the side rail
and put myself in good line right when
you're feeling the pressure and things
are tough try to keep it as simple as
possible stay in line that's your game
plan there right I'm a little bit
straight in so I can do all kind of
crazy stuff here I can bounce it off the
rail I can draw it all the way all the
way back but I'm thinking you know what
I kind of have position already
the eight ball goes in both corner
pockets so all I have to do is get the
death side of the table there and now
I'm straight in I can just roll it
forward and shoot the nine in the
opposite one so the mental framework
paid off there I did work in the chair
right I reminded myself what I have to
do focused on the breathing very big and
I'm back in the game as we see here
during this match I take the lead I was
down five three
I made it five five Dennis pulled ahead
six five again I had to run a tough rack
I made it six six broken ran out four
seven six and now I'm on the hill first
breaking to try and win this game one
pulled down two balls open and I get a
shot on the two so right here what's
interesting mentally is I feel I have an
opportunity to win this match over a guy
that's beating me the last three years
mom stop
so I'm getting a little bit excited
right now the trick is which what you
will learn in the course also excitement
is actually a good thing
right that's what gets us in the zone it
gives us passion motivation energy all
good stuff but over-excitement
getting over amped that takes your focus
away now your ego starts kicking in I'm
gonna do this I'm gonna beat this guy
I'm gonna get in blah blah blah all that
internal chatter is already chatter and
it's distracting to you from what you
have to do which is to run this rack so
I caught myself in the moment actually
already when I put my Q's back back to
the game plan what do I have to do to
win this match what do I have to do to
Denis in this match is to play the shots
as good as I can so I'm really focusing
on execution here putting the cue ball
in the right line and trying to give
myself easy shots right under pressure
when the arm is not feeling well what's
important is that you try to give
yourself easy shots lower your
expectations a little bit right you're
not Superman all the time sometimes it's
about putting yourself in simple
positions over and over again and then
your confidence will start growing so
I'm not feeling too bad here I ran the
last two racks already in a row so my
arms getting nice and loose and I'm
feeling the speed if the table much
better now it's the end of the second
match I'm playing on this table so as
you can see I got the speed down pretty
well I put myself in good line and this
is really where I'm forcing myself to
focus on the balls because I'm almost
out there they're laying right there but
this shot here for example I could have
easily over drew that or under drew drew
it and I would have been out of position
but I'm sitting well once again I'm
checking my angle I don't want to be
absolutely straight on the seven where I
have to maybe shoot a tricky eight I am
making sure here that I got the right
angle to close this out closing out guys
that's huge
that's what I've learned from champions
like Ralph sookay Johnnie Archer in
critical situations they've learned me
to take sometimes a little bit of extra
time keep keep the right angles and then
it will present itself much easier so
I've done that the entire rack stuck to
the game plan and I'm almost here
rewarding myself with a big win
me in the next round I'm already
celebrating there we go
I get to celebrate a little bit happy
with that and off we go to the next
round
[Music]
you